Okay. Let's turn our attention now to working with
现在 我们来看一下 Excel 文件
Excel documents. What I'd like to use is an example
在这里 我用作示例的数据是
here, [SOUND] is data from the Electric Reliability Council of
德州电力可靠性委员会的数据
Texas. This is an organization that manages the flow of
这是一个管理上百万德州用户用电流量的组织
electricity to millions of Texas customers. They also provide
它们还会向公众提供
a lot of publicly available datasets. On things like load,
很多有关供电量
or the amount of electricity that's used by their customers.
或其用户用电量的数据集
This is one such example for the calendar year 2013.
这里的数据就是日历年2003年的数据
A lot of organizations publish this type of
很多组织都会发布这样的数据
data. And often they will publish it as Excel
他们通常会以 Excel 的文件形式发布
documents. What that means for us is that we
这意味着 我们需要知道
have to have a way of programmatically working with
如何以程序化模式处理 Excel 文件
Excel because many times, we'll want to process dozens
因为 在大多数情况下
or perhaps hundreds of files all of which have
我们需要处理数十个 甚至数百个 Excel 格式的文件
been published as Excel. What I'd like to introduce
在这里 我要向你介绍
you to here is a python module called XLRD.
名为 XLRD 的 python 模块
XLRD allows us to work with Excel files whether it's the old XLS format or the
XLRD 可以处理老式的 XLS 格式和新的XLSX 格式的 Excel 文件
new XLSX format. This module will allow us to read-in all of the data from
利用这个模块 我们可以载入 excel 工作薄中的所有数据
an excel workbook and, work with it in any way that we need to in a
并在 Python 程序中对其进行各种处理
Python program. There's also an XLWT module, which
还有个名为 XLWT 模块
allows us to create Excel files, if we
如有需要
need to do that programatically. Okay so the first thing
我们可以利用它 以程序化模式创建 Excel 文件
that I want to do before we dive in and
在浏览这个示例代码前
take a look at this example code is actually go
我首先要运行它
through and run it. Okay. What I've done with this program
我对这个程序进行的处理就是
is produce output that illustrates a lot of the features
使其生成的输出能够描述
that you might want to work with when using XRLD one
在使用 XRLD 处理 excel 数据时可能用到的功能
processing excel data. So, one of the things I would
我要说明的一点是
like to illustrate here, is how we can read our data
我们应该怎样将 Excel 文件中的数据
from an Excel file entirely into python list and work
完全读取成 python 列表并对其进行处理
with it. How we go about working with rows and
我们要如何在 Excel 文件中
columns and individual cells in an Excel file using the
利用 XLRD 模块处理行、列和单元格
XLRD module. And then finally, a little bit of information about
最后 我还要讲一下日期的问题
dates. This is primarily because of the way that dates
主要是因为日期在 XML 中显示的形式各有不同
are represented in XML that we need to talk about this.
所以 我们要讨论一下
So let's go back and look at this code. Here
我们回头看一下这个代码
we're simply specifying which file it is that we're going to load.
这里 我们只设置了要载入的文件
And in this case, it's an XLS file, an old
在这种情况下 载入的是 XLS 文件
format Microsoft Excel file. Okay? And then, the bulk of the
它是微软 Excel 文件的老版格式
work that we're doing here is actually done in the Parse
然后 我们要进行的部分工作其实已经在解析文件函数中完成了
File function. Alright so this is the command we use to
这是用来打开工作簿的命令
open a workbook and you note that we're using the same
注意 我们这里用的是同一个变量名
variable name her okay? Then we need to specify each sheet
然后 我们要设置有待处理的每个工作表
we'd like to work with. So here we're selecting the sheet
所以 在这里 我们选择 工作表0
zero and you'll find that XLRD is entirely zero based indexing.
你会发现 XLRD 的索引是建立在0的基础上的
So the very first column is actually column
第一列其实是第0列
zero, the first row is actually row zero. Okay,
第一行其实是第0行
here's an example of doing a list comprehension,
这里是列表解析的示例
and in this case, what we're doing is essentially
在这里
looping through all of the rows and columns and reading all of
我们其实是在遍历所有行和列
that data into a Python list. What I'm doing here, then,
并将所有数据读取成 Python 列表
is simply printing out the value of Row Three and Column Two
这里就是打出 我们刚刚生成列表中的
for this list that we've just generated. Now if I
第3行和第2列的值
scroll down a little bit, we can see that following the
如果我把页面向下拉 可以看到
list comprehension piece, what we're doing here is looping through the
在下一个列表解析代码中 我们是要遍历整个工作簿
entire sheet one row at a time, and then moving across
但每次只遍历一行 然后在列中进行移动
the columns. And the way that I've set this up,
我把代码设置为
is that once we get to row 50, what we're going
使其当我们遍历至第50行时
to do is essentially is print out the values in that
就把这一行的所有值都打出来
particular row. One column at a time. Now again, this is
但每次只打一列
a piece of code that does nothing more than
这段代码只是在演示
simply illustrate the functions and methods that you'll want
使用 XLRD 时
to work with when using XLRD. In the next
你可能会用到的函数和方法
piece of our example code, I'm illustrating how to work
在下一个示例代码中
with rows and columns in XLRD. Alright, in this
我要演示如何在 XLRD 中处理行和列
case what we're going to do here is we're
在这里 我们要做的是
going to simply grab the number of rows for
取出这个工作表的行数
this particular sheet. And then we'll print that out, alright.
然后把它打出来
This is an illustration of how to check the
这里演示的是如何查看
data type, or the value type, for a particular cell.
某一单元格的数据或值的类型
Using the cell type method, for sheet, for objects
这个要针对工作表 或类型工作表的对象
of type sheet, okay? Then cell value. This actually gets
使用单元格类型方法 然后 这是单元格的值
the value that's stored in that cell as the
它能以适当的 Python 值形式取出保存在这个单元格中的值
appropriate Python value. Whether it's a floating point value or
无论这个值是浮点值还是其他值
something else. And then finally this is actually [SOUND]
最后这个方法很棒
a pretty cool method. Here, we can slice the values
在这里 我们可以将某一列中的值进行切片
out of a particular column. What that means it that
它的意思是
we could say, okay, I want three values from this particular
比如 我想要这一列中的三个值
column and I want to to start on row one, so
从第一行开始取
actually the second row down. And I want to go through
然后向下经过第1、第2和第3行
rows one, two, and three. Up to row four but
一直到第四行 但不包括第四行
not including row four. And I want to take those three
我想取出这一列的这三个值
values sliced out of that particular column. Okay. And then here
然后我们要做的
we are doing something very similar to what we did here.
其实和这里差不多
Which is actually checking the type of the value in
也就是检查该单元格中位数的类型
the given cell. But in this case we have a
在这种情况下 单元格里是日期
date in this cell Okay. So, we're going to pull out
所以 我们要取出单元格中的值
the cell value. Now, it turns out that, in the old
事实上 在老式的 Excel 格式中
Excel format, dates were represented simply as floating point numbers.
日期直接显示为浮点数
So what we can do is use the XLRD date
所以 我们可以利用 XLRD_date_as_tuple 的方法
as tuple method to get us that time in a
获得这个时间
way that allows us to work with it as a date
以使我们可以在 Python 中把它当作日期处理
in Python. Okay, let's go look at that output one
我们再来看一下输出结果
more time. Okay, so here's our list comprehension. We're simply
这是我们的列表解析
printing out the value at row 3, column 2 from
我们只是在所有数据读取成的列表中
the list into which we read all of the excel data.
打出了第3行和第2列的值
So here we can see where I was looping through
我们可以看到
the rows and columns and printed out all of the values
我遍历了所有行和列并打出了第50行的所有值
on row fifty Okay, and then number of rows in
这个工作表的行数是7200
this sheet happens to be more than 7200. Alright? Now note
这里注意一下
here that the type of data in cell two,
单元格2的数据类型为2
is specified as two. You can look up, if you
如果有兴趣 你可以查看 XLRD 文件
want to, in the XLRD documentation Exactly what all of
找出这些不同的类型标识分别代表什么
these different type identifiers reference. In this case it's a
在这里
floating point number. We can see that the value that
它代表浮点数
we've got there is 1,036 and change, okay? And here's
可以看到 这里的值是1036 后面还有小数
the output from having taking a slice out of Column
这里是第3列切片的输出结果
Three. Okay, so here's that piece where we were working
这里是我们处理的日期部分
with dates. Now XLRD does distinguish the fact that that
XLRD 确实能辨别出这个单元格里有日期
particular cell holds a date. But here's the time, represented
但这里的日期是用浮点数表示的
as a floating point number. Okay? What we can do
我们要做的就是
is convert this to a Python datetime tuple Using that XLRD
利用我告诉你的 XLRD 方法
method that I showed you. And this gives us a
将它转换成 Python 日期元组
much better representation of the data that we're interested in. So,
这样以来 这个数据的表现形式就更符合我们的要求了
in this case, what we've got is, row one, column
在这里 我们得到的是第1行和第0列
zero. So it's that very first cell at the top, okay?
也就是最上方的第一个单元格
This one here, right? And note that what we're pulling out there
就是这个 注意 我们取出作为值的数据
as the value is, in fact, year 2013, January 1st, 1 AM.
其实是2013年1月1日上午1点